Cliff Lloyd fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Cliff Lloyd fonds
1950 - 1980
F-143
Q106659700
32 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Lloyd, Cliff
Cliff L. Lloyd was a professor in the Department of Economics and Commerce from 1973 until his sudden death on January 24, 1977. As an experimental economist, he is remembered for his proposed Northern Stores project, an attempt to investigate demand theory (would people buy less of a product if it cost more). For a fuller appreciation of Lloyd's research, see the introductory essays by his SFU colleagues in The Collected Works of Cliff L. Lloyd (F-143-2-0-11).
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records made and received by Cliff Lloyd in his role as a professor. Includes correspondence, publications, research proposals, course materials and other documents.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Department of Economics; Business and commerce
Unknown
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
The files are open with no restrictions.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. Biographical data is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room. See also the article about the Northern Stores Project from Saturday Night (February 1996).
- The Northern Stores project, 1964 - 1979; F-143-1; 13 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to Lloyd's proposed Northern Stores project, for which he never received funding. The project is described in the Saturday Night article available in the hard copy finding aid. Includes correspondence, grant applications, questionnaires and other documents.
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist.
  No further accruals to the series are expected.
  The files are open with no restrictions.
  A file list is available. Biographical data of Cliff L. Lloyd and the article about the Northern Shore Project from Saturday Night (February 1996) by Peter Shawn Taylor are included in the appendices to this finding aid (hard copy version aid only, available in the Archives Reading Room).
  - The Northern Stores project master copy of manuscript, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-143-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Hudson's Bay Company - general background, 1964 - 1969; F-143-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Hudson's Bay Company - correspondence, 1971 - 1972; F-143-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Transportation costs, 1975; F-143-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Notes on procedure, 1972; F-143-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Northern Labrador Services Division, 1972; F-143-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Hudson's Bay Company - Northern Stores (likely), [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-143-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Hudson's Bay Company - Northern Stores (rejected), [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-143-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Grant proposal - Canada Council, 1974; F-143-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Grant proposal - Canada Council, 1975; F-143-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Grant proposal - Killam Senior Research Scholarship, 1975; F-143-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Grant proposal - National Research Council Canada, 1975; F-143-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
  - Northern Shores proposal, 1972 - 1974; F-143-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 143-1)
- Teaching and research files, 1950 - 1980; F-143-2; 19 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files relating to Lloyd's teaching and research activities. Includes published and unpublished papers, notes, correspondence, and course-related material such class outlines and exams.
  A file list is available.
  - Papers, [ca 1950] - [ca 1959]; F-143-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Thesis notes, [ca 1960] - [ca 1969]; F-143-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Correspondence relating to first book, 1963 - 1978; F-143-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Consultant report, 1964 - 1965; F-143-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Course related material, 1976; F-143-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 - 1974; F-143-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Correspondence, 1975; F-143-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Correspondence, 1976; F-143-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 143-2)
  - Correspondence, 1977 - 1978; F-143-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - small 143-3)
  - Correspondence with Judy Alexander, 1971 - 1974; F-143-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - small 143-3)
  - The Collected Works of Cliff L. Lloyd, 1980; F-143-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - small 143-3)
  - Publications and correspondence, vol. 1, 1968 - 1975; F-143-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - small 143-3)
  - Publications and correspondence, vol. 2, 1968 - 1975; F-143-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - small 143-3)